<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kaitai Liang | Manos Panaousis</title>
    <link>http://manospanaousis.com/author/kaitai-liang/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://manospanaousis.com/author/kaitai-liang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Kaitai Liang</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://manospanaousis.com/images/icon_hu74af10c7cd92758fcd76dc0e85abbbae_20356_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Kaitai Liang</title>
      <link>http://manospanaousis.com/author/kaitai-liang/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>SECONDO: a Security ECONomics service platform for smart security investments and cyber insurance pricing in the beyonD 2020 netwOrking era</title>
      <link>http://manospanaousis.com/project/secondo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://manospanaousis.com/project/secondo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SECONDO addresses the question “How can decisions about &lt;strong&gt;cyber security investments&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;cyber insurance&lt;/strong&gt; pricing be optimised?” SECONDO will support professionals who seek cyber security investments, developed to support human decision making, and a complete well-founded security strategy. This is a timely research problem, as the rapid growth of cyber-attacks is expected to continue its upwards trajectory. Such growth presents a prominent threat to normal business operations and the EU society itself. On the other hand, an interesting, well-known, finding is that an organisation&amp;rsquo;s computer systems may be less secure than a competitor&amp;rsquo;s, despite having spent more money in securing them. Budget setting, cyber security investment choices and cyber insurance, in the face of uncertainties, are highly challenging tasks with massive business implications. SECONDO aims to make impact on the operation of EU businesses who often: (i) have a limited cyber security budget; and (ii) ignore the importance of cyber insurance. Cyber insurance can play a critical role to the mitigation of cyber risk. This can be done by imposing a cost on firms&amp;rsquo; cyber risk through a premium that they have to pay and the potential for paying a smaller premium should they reduce their current cyber security risk. SECONDO has a cross-disciplinary nature, combining mathematical and engineering insights to empower innovative software. Apart from the novel research results, the project will offer a software platform to narrow the gap between theoretical understanding and practice. To achieve this, the four industrial project partners will (i) lead the part of the project where industrial needs will be entered as input to the requirements collection phase, and, (ii) provide their innovative software for risk assessment. The three academic partners will work together to (i) design and thoroughly describe the proposed methodologies, but also (ii) contribute to their software development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Budget&lt;/strong&gt;: €1.6M (University of Greenwich share €238k).&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Principal Investigator&lt;/strong&gt;: Manos Panaousis.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Partners&lt;/strong&gt;: Can be found 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cordis.europa.eu/project/id/823997&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Role&lt;/strong&gt;: Leading research in cybersecurity economics, digital asset pricing, optimal cyber insurance premiums and coverage, extending OST for an IoT cybersecurity use case (Work Package leader: Dissemination, Standardisation and Exploitation).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CUREX: seCUre and pRivate hEalth data eXchange</title>
      <link>http://manospanaousis.com/project/curex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://manospanaousis.com/project/curex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Health sector’s increasing dependence on digital information and communication infrastructures renders it vulnerable to threats to privacy and cybersecurity, especially as the theft of health data has become particularly lucrative for cyber criminals. At the same time, a breach of integrity of health data can have &lt;strong&gt;dramatic consequences for the patients affected&lt;/strong&gt;. CUREX addresses comprehensively the protection of the confidentiality and integrity of health data by producing a novel, flexible and scalable situational awareness-oriented platform. It allows a healthcare provider to assess the realistic cybersecurity and privacy risks they are exposed to and &lt;strong&gt;suggest mathematically optimal strategies for addressing these risks with safeguards tailored specifically for each business case and application&lt;/strong&gt;. CUREX is fully GDPR compliant by design. At its core, a decentralised architecture enhanced with a private blockchain infrastructure ensures the integrity of the risk assessment process and of all data transactions that occur between the diverse range of stakeholders involved. Crucially, CUREX expands beyond technical measures and places emphasis also on improving cyber hygiene through training and raising awareness activities for a healthcare institution’s personnel. Its validation focuses on the highly challenging condition of (cross-border) health data exchange, spanning &lt;strong&gt;patient cross-border mobility&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;remote healthcare&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;data exchange for research&lt;/strong&gt;. CUREX consortium will also utilise the outcomes of the well-known MyHealthMyData project in a dedicated demonstration that will use their blockchain-enabled platform which will control the actual data exchange. We envisage that CUREX will impact the European market developing one of the first blockchain platform for risk assessment management under the GDPR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Budget&lt;/strong&gt;: €4,987,825 (University of Greenwich share €311,097, University of Surrey €39,478).&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Principal Investigator&lt;/strong&gt;: Manos Panaousis.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Partners&lt;/strong&gt;: Can be found 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cordis.europa.eu/project/id/826404&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Acceptance Rate&lt;/strong&gt;: 6/46.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Role&lt;/strong&gt;: Leading research in optimisation of cyber controls and lead the development of the Optimal Safeguards Tool (OST) for a healthcare cybersecurity use case (Work Package leader: Risk Management for Health Data Exchange).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPEAR: Secure and PrivatE smArt gRid</title>
      <link>http://manospanaousis.com/project/spear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://manospanaousis.com/project/spear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last decade, cyber-attacks have become increasingly sophisticated, stealthy, targeted and multi-faceted which may leverage zero-day exploits and highly creative interdisciplinary attack methods. As our society is becoming increasingly dependent on Critical INfrastructures (CIN), new technologies are needed to increase our detection and response capabilities. Detecting and responding to such attacks by a highly motivated, skilled and well-funded attacker has however been proven highly challenging. One of the most vulnerable and high-impact CIN is the Smart Grid. Smart Grid is considered as the next-generation power system, which promises self-healing, resilience, sustainability and efficiency to the energy Critical Infrastructures (CIN). However, securing smart grids against cyber-attacks is of vital importance for National Security and Public Safety, since the collapse of an energy production utility may cause human lives, millions of euros, denial of a very important and common good such as energy and days or even months of recovering. To this end, the SPEAR proposal aims at a) detecting and responding to cyber-attacks using new technologies and capabilities, b) detecting threat and anomalies timely, c) developing all-in-one security detection solutions, d) leveraging advanced forensics subject to privacy-preserving, e) confronting Advanced Persistent Threat (APT) and targeted attacks in smart grids, f) increasing the resilience of the smart grid innovation, g) alleviating the lack of trust in smart grid operators and h) empowering EU-wide consensus. Within SPEAR, four proof-of-concept Use Cases are planned in order to validate and assess the implemented security and privacy tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Budget&lt;/strong&gt;: €2,965,597 (University of Surrey share €283,760).&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Principal Investigator&lt;/strong&gt;: Manos Panaousis, &lt;strong&gt;Co-Investigators&lt;/strong&gt;: Kaitai Liang, Steve Schneider.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Partners&lt;/strong&gt;: Can be found 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cordis.europa.eu/project/id/787011&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Acceptance Rate&lt;/strong&gt;: 4/63.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Role&lt;/strong&gt;: Leading research on intrusion detection and reputation management (Work package 3 leader: Cyber Attack Detection in Smart Grid).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
